Finn Thompson

www.finnthompson.me in linkedin.com/in/nnifinn

I am passionate about designing and delivering excellent object-oriented software solutions.

I have programmed extracurricularly for 8+ years while cultivating a user-focused mentality through my education.

Currently looking for an entry level position as a software engineer.

Skills

Programming: Java, JavaScript, Python, HTML, CSS, Regex, React.js, Node.js, MySQL, Unit Testing (Jest)
Technologies: Git, Markdown, VSCode, IntelliJ, Windows, Linux, Arduino, Figma, Chrome Extensions
Holistic Skills: UX design, Agile, technical writing, usability research, teamwork, communication

Online Activity: GitHub (15+ repositories), Stack Overflow (23k+ reputation)

Projects

Smart Prescription Management Device (Team Capstone)

Python, UI/UX, Research

- Developed a component framework in Python and C to control the device and its touchscreen UI
- Designed, developed, and assembled Arduino and Raspberry Pi prototypes
- Led a usability research study to evaluate the first iteration of the prototype

Various JavaScript Libraries, Published with Documentation

JavaScript, Tech Writing

- FormPersistence.js persist form data across page refreshes (featured in JavaScript Weekly)
- Gamepads.js add enhanced HTML5 gamepad support including button events and icons
- Pseudo:styler toggle CSS pseudo class styles on elements (co-developer)

Netflix Controller Chrome Extension

JavaScript, UI/UX

• Chrome extension providing an intuitive interface for controlling Netflix with a gamepad

UW Course Seat Claimer

Java, UI/UX

• Java GUI application that registers for classes when open seat email notifications are received

Education

University of Washington

Seattle, WA

B.S. in Human Centered Design and Engineering

Sept. 2014 - June 2018

- GPA: 3.65 overall, 3.8 in major
- Includes Computer Programming II, Web Programming, Physical Computing, Interactive Systems Design

Experience

Shift Supervisor, Starbucks

Seattle, WA

• Empowered a team of baristas to deliver exceptional customer experiences

Oct. 2016 - Dec. 2018

• Sustained customer ratings as one of the top stores in its district

Research Intern, Scripps Translational Science Institute

La Jolla, CA

- Developed a Java GUI application to save researchers time identifying gene relationships
 May 2014 June 2014
- Designed a term frequency–inverse document frequency algorithm to rank results

Developer / Project Creator, RuneDream

Reno, NV

Developed a Java application to automate RuneScape gameplay, downloaded 50k+ times

Jan. 2012 - May 2013

• Worked with a team to create a website, forum, and plugin API to support the application